About

Big fan of Linux, Docker, Python, Open Source and automation. Looking every day for the best frameworks, tools, etc... Continuous Improvement is my life. Quality, Customer Intimacy, Knowledge Sharing, Openness and being Respectful to others is what I follow every day.

All this results in 15+ years of experience in IT ranging from Software Engineering to Solutions Engineering.

One sentence: Just inject the coffee into my jugular vein!

What I do: I get it working. I'm specialized in Python, Java, Bash, Linux, Docker and k8s.

Skills: Python, Java, Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, Shell Scripting, Bash, Javascript, Scrum, React.js, CI/CD, DevOps, DevSecOps, AIOps, . . .

Achievements

- Launched OpenFaas (serverless for k8s) within StackState.
- Fixed the base64 encoding check for the gcloud GitHub Action.
- Presented at AIOps Expo: The AIOps Maturity model.
- Fixed containerd cri authentication documentation. See PR 1375.
- For Snyk, I've helped creating and releasing pysnyk. A SDK for integrating with the Snyk REST api.
- For XebiaLabs, I've created from scratch the XebiaLabs Community, consisting of 200+ integrations within the CI/CD space written in Python and Java.

Education & Certifications

- Master in Computer Sciences: Ghent University (Belgium) | 1999 2003
- Python Basics: Coursera University of Michigan | Oct 2020
- Professional Scrum Developer: Scrum.org | 2013
- Professional Scrum Master: Scrum.org | 2011
- Certified Scrum Master: Scrum Alliance | 2010
- HackerRank: Java and Python gold level
- StackOverflow: Supporter, Revival, Informed and Teacher badges

Experience:

• StackState: Solutions Engineer | Dec 2019 - Current

At StackState my main responsibility is to create multiple demo scenario using k8s, Helm and OpenFaas. These scenario's can show the different use cases, relevant within AIOps and Unified Observability.

Besides the demo scenario I've als created an integration between Nginx+ and StackState and introduced knowledge management using Notion.

• Snyk: Solutions Engineer | May 2019 - Dec 2019 I helped on the development of pysnyk, a Python based SDK for the Snyk REST API. Besides the development, I also managed to close several deals. Some examples: Mattel, Verizon Media, Compass, Box.com, etc...

• XebiaLabs: Solutions Engineer | 2013 - 2019

My main focus was helping companies move towards Continuous Delivery and supporting them using the products provided by XebiaLabs (XL Platform). Some examples are UHG, Electronic Arts, Nike, Capital Group, KPMG, ...

For XebiaLabs I also maintained the community platform which contains 200+ different integrations written in Python and Java.

• Xebia: Senior Consultant | 2012 - 2013

I've worked as Senior Consultant for Xebia, where I did multiple implementations within the Continuous Delivery domain for companies like UWV (Netherlands), ING, Bol.com, etc. In this period I also became a Professional Scrum Trainer with Scrum.org.

Capgemini: Java Architect, Scrum Master, People Manager | 2009 - 2012
I worked for Capgemini as a consultant in the Java domain. For Capgemini I took up different roles like Java Architect, Scrum Master, People Manager, ...

I was also a core member of the Belgium Java Community and the Belgium Agile/Scrum community within Cappemini.

• RealDolmen: Software Engineer | 2007 - 2009

I was a member of the Java Competence Center and responsible for the technical analysis and lead of several projects based on the Java platform within RealDolmen. The main focus was on creating Java based web applications using advanced state of the art technologies.

I was also the co-founder of the JBoss User group and member of the Ubuntu user group.

• Barco: Software R&D Engineer | 2003 - 2006

Introduced new technologies in the research department with as target the development of a new business application to control video display walls. I led and managed several projects in Belgium and also outsourced in India.

Aside from the typical research and development tasks I also took responsibility in European research projects in cooperation with several universities.